<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Front Page on GVPT</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Front Page on GVPT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflict in World Politics</title>
      <link>/classes/southafrica_uc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/southafrica_uc/</guid>
      <description>In this course we examine conflict in world politics. We focus on: the analysis of conflict; causes of conflict; actors in conflict; behaviour during conflict; consequences of conflict; and moral evaluation of conflict. In each dimension, we ask questions. To each of these questions, there are different, even opposing, answers. We examine these answers, illustrating them with cases and/or empirical material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elections and Voters in Britain and the United States</title>
      <link>/classes/uk_manchester/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/uk_manchester/</guid>
      <description>The University of Manchester was ranked in the top ten in the UK for politics and international studies, in both the QS and Times Higher Education World University Rankings 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>/classes/cuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/cuba/</guid>
      <description>Materials  Memorandum of Understanding Promotional Flyer Itinerary  Description This is a new course that combines lectures on campus in College Park with a study abroad component in Havana, Cuba.
 The lectures on campus will focus on different strategies for studying foreign policy decision making.
 The class will travel to Cuba to learn about several foreign policy events that shaped much of the foreign policy of the United States in this region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Human Rights</title>
      <link>/classes/brazil_ufsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/brazil_ufsc/</guid>
      <description>The Office of International Relations (SINTER) of Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina (UFSC) aims at promoting the interaction between the university and other international higher education institutions and organizations; establishing and giving support to technical, scientific and cultural cooperation agreements; and providing exchange opportunities for UFSC students, faculty and administrative staff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Political Economy</title>
      <link>/classes/scotland_uoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/scotland_uoe/</guid>
      <description>The course begins with a review of the principal theoretical approaches to the study of international political economy. It then examines the major issue areas in the post-World War 2 global economy, including: trade, transnational corporations, international finance including debt crises; international finance, development, globalization and regionalization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Terrorism</title>
      <link>/classes/spain_slu_madrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/spain_slu_madrid/</guid>
      <description>SLU-Madrid’s political science program fosters a theoretical and empirical understanding of complex international processes that are increasingly important to all nations. The goal is to form leaders who understand the world today and have the tools to analyze key developments in global politics critically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin American Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>/classes/argentia_udesa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/argentia_udesa/</guid>
      <description>Designed for students who are interested in learning first-hand about Latin America, the Program in Latin American Studies offers the possibility of choosing among a wide range of courses in different disciplines with significant Latin American Studies content. Our courses are taught by Universidad de San Andrés faculty who are accomplished scholars with research agendas and experience teaching in foreign universities.
Intended for students at the intermediate Spanish-language level and above, our program complements classroom learning with periodic field trips and cultural activities that introduce students to diverse aspects of life and culture in Argentina.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peace and Conflict</title>
      <link>/classes/kosovo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/kosovo/</guid>
      <description>For more information, check out the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Opinion</title>
      <link>/classes/france/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/france/</guid>
      <description>This is a course in development that will look at public opinion in Paris, France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security and Insecurity in Northeast Asia</title>
      <link>/classes/southkorea_yonsei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/southkorea_yonsei/</guid>
      <description>Being the oldest private university in Korea, Yonsei University was first established in 1885 by Christian missionaries. Our mission is to educate leaders who will contribute to humanity in the spirit of “truth and freedom.” The 300,000 Yonsei alumni who take this calling to heart can be found manifesting this proud spirit from leadership positions around the world.
Yonsei’s main campus is ensconced in a spacious, picturesque and natural setting located minutes away from the economic, political, and cultural centers of Seoul’s metropolitan downtown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability Politics, Paradigms, and Debates</title>
      <link>/classes/netherlands_uva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/netherlands_uva/</guid>
      <description>Politics is how communities settle their differences and achieve their goals. As a result, politics is everywhere and at all levels from the local to the global. The programme offers a broad orientation in International Relations, Political Economy, Public Policy and Governance, Comparative Politics and Political Theory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>